<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Jin Chen</title>
    <link>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://academic-demo.netlify.app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Jin Chen</description>
    <generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/media/icon_hua2ec155b4296a9c9791d015323e16eb5_11927_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url>
      <title>Jin Chen</title>
      <link>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>COMM420 Research Methods in Advertising and Public Relations</title>
      <link>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/teaching/_comm420/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/teaching/_comm420/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-description&#34;&gt;Course description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Advertising and public relations practice involves using research to make decisions – often big decisions with big price tags. This course provides students with the tools to outline, execute and evaluate mass media research. The primary focus is on using research for advertising and public relations program and campaign management—planning, monitoring and evaluating. You will learn the most important research methods used in the field – content analysis, focus groups, in-depth interviews, surveys, and experiments – and gain experience with the statistical and textual analysis methods most often used to analyze results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-objectives&#34;&gt;Course objectives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;By the end of this semester, students will be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demonstrate an understanding of the diversity of audiences in relationship to communications;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Understand concepts and apply theories in the use and presentation of images and information;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demonstrate an understanding of professional ethical principles and work ethically;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Think critically, creatively and independently;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Conduct research and evaluate information by methods appropriate to the communications professions in which they work;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Write correctly and clearly;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply basic numerical and statistical concepts;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apply tools and technologies commonly used in communications practices;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Know the difference between primary and secondary research, and their uses;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Develop a primary research project including research objectives, sample justification, data collection, data analysis, and data interpretation;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Use statistical software (e.g., SPSS) to analyze data;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Present both secondary and primary research in a comprehensive, well-organized report.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;syllabus--lecture-slides&#34;&gt;Syllabus &amp;amp; Lecture Slides&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VIEW &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.app/uploads/Comm420%20syllabus.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SYLLABUS&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Theory Module: &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.app/uploads/L8%20Level%20of%20Measurement.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Measurement Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Survey Module: &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.app/uploads/Qualtrics%20Tutorial.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Qualtrics Tutorial Slides&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COMM310 Digital Media Metrics</title>
      <link>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/teaching/_comm310/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/teaching/_comm310/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-description&#34;&gt;Course description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course is an introduction to the methods for collecting, analyzing and utilizing audience data for traditional and new media. The class will cover the fundamentals of traditional media audience analysis, web metrics, and social media metrics, specifically as they relate to audience measurement, advertising campaign evaluation and content distribution. Students will learn the methods of data collection, analysis and use for traditional broadcast media, and the transformation of these practices in the newly digitized and converged multiplatform, multiscreen environment. The course will also cover the basics of data capture for new media (at an appropriate technical level), and the use of this data for the design of metrics appropriate for various purposes such as monitoring traffic, conversions and revenue generation. The use of metrics in pricing models for advertising, sales generation and content distribution will also be covered. Students will be introduced to data sources for digital media audience analysis, with a special focus on Google Analytics. Students passing this class would be able to pass the Google Analytics Individual Qualification test.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-objectives&#34;&gt;Course objectives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understand metrics and key performance indicators for web analytics and social media metrics; sources of data for new media, including web analytics platforms such as Google Analytics, online surveys and competitive intelligence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Prepare students to take the Google Analytics Individual Qualification (GAIQ) certification exam.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Learn key skills such as quantification, basic statistical tests, reasoning with numbers, performance measurement and tracking, financial metrics.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The course is for students who intend to pursue careers in web analytics, digital analytics, social media analytics, or in new media departments of traditional content providers.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Taxing or Relaxing? Retrospective Responses to Video Games in Relation to Demand</title>
      <link>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/project/_video-game-recovery/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/project/_video-game-recovery/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This paper explores the self-reported impact of playing video games of varied intensities on perceptions of emotion regulation and recovery during times of stress and addresses in-game demand as a prominent factor contributing to differences in gaming experiences. In a within-subjects retrospective study, participants (N = 218) were asked to recall both an easy game and a challenging game that they play regularly and rate the two experiences. Results demonstrated notable distinctions between the recollections of playing these two classes of video games on user experiences. Both types of games were perceived to lower self-reported negative emotions among the participants, with easy games tending to correlate with higher positive emotions for users post game. While both classes of games did not differ in relation to self-reported recovery, easy games were associated with more relaxation and less mastery. Implications of these findings for video game studies and game design are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>“This Video is Sponsored!” The Role of User Danmaku Disclosure on  Evaluations of Influencer Marketing</title>
      <link>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/project/_danmaku-disclosure/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/project/_danmaku-disclosure/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Prior studies have documented the effects of sponsorship disclosures, however, much of the prior work has focused on traditional disclosure sources with less consideration of the new interactive media context. The present work examines the effect of user Danmaku, as a novel source of sponsorship disclosure, on both conceptual and attitudinal aspects of persuasion knowledge, as well as brand outcomes. We conducted a 3 (disclosure type: none vs. influencer vs. Danmaku disclosure) x 2 (ad position: beginning vs. end of the video) between-subject factorial experiment among a native Chinese sample. The results showed that Danmaku and influencer disclosure were equally effective on ad recognition but differed in attitudinal persuasion knowledge as Danmaku disclosure induced greater dislike, skepticism, and perceived inappropriateness. There was no effect of sponsorship placement on outcome variables. Furthermore, ad recognition affected brand outcomes via attitudinal persuasion knowledge. Based on the findings, theoretical and practical implications are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COMM100N The Mass Media and Society</title>
      <link>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/teaching/_comm100n/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 10 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/teaching/_comm100n/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-description&#34;&gt;Course description&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Mass Media and Society is an overview of the interaction between mass media and society. By drawing from selected topics, the course pays particular attention to the social influences (e.g., economics, politics, technology, law and culture) that shape media messages. Among others, the course examines the nature of media controllers as well as the character of &amp;ldquo;users&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;consumers&amp;rdquo; of media products. By so doing, students are informed about the overall structure and scope of the mass media and led to understand the power and influences associated with media messages and practices. By the end of the semester, each student should have a better understanding of the dynamic nature of the mass media in an information society.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-objectives&#34;&gt;Course Objectives&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At the completion of this course, you should be able to:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Describe the different functions of the mass media;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Describe the process and theory of mass communication;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain the basic concepts relevant to the various media forms;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Demonstrate an awareness of the media as social, political and cultural forces;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;List the formal and informal controls on the mass media;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain current trends and changes in the mass media including those influenced by new technologies;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explain the practices and processes of media support systems/industries;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Discuss varied issues including those ethical concerns pertinent to media and the public.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tailoring Your AI Friend</title>
      <link>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/project/_ai-friend/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/project/_ai-friend/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Will people like their companion chatbot and enjoy the interaction more if given the choice to customize it? If so, why? We investigated these questions with an experiment in which participants in the customization group (N = 85) were given the options to choose the name, gender, and personality of a text-based companion chatbot while those in the control condition (N = 82) randomly received chatbots matched with the customization choices made by participants in the experimental group (a yoked control design). Data showed that providing customization had positive indirect effects on user perception of the chatbot, enjoyment of the interaction, and future use intentions via perceived customization, sense of control, sense of identity, homophily, and expectation violation. In addition, users’ perceived levels of customization contributed positively to user perceptions of homophily and identity, with these relationships being moderated by individual differences in perceptions of machines and technology use respectively.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>COMS100 Public Speaking</title>
      <link>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/teaching/_com100/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/teaching/_com100/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;course-objective&#34;&gt;Course Objective:&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This course will focus on the development of public speaking and listening skills required for effective communication in a variety of contexts. Improvement of these skills will help you process and evaluate messages as well as adapt your communication to diverse audiences and settings. Students are expected to show increased skill development and to better understand varying perspectives from assignment and assignment.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;syllabus--slides&#34;&gt;Syllabus &amp;amp; Slides&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VIEW &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.app/uploads/COM100%20syllabus.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;SYLLABUS&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.app/uploads/COMS100.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Sample Slide&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;sample-assignment&#34;&gt;Sample Assignment&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VIEW &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.app/uploads/persuasive%20speech.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Persuasive Speech Assignment&lt;/a&gt; &amp;amp; &lt;a href=&#34;https://academic-demo.netlify.app/uploads/speech%20rubic.pdf&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Rubric&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Should Chatbot Ads Be Chatty</title>
      <link>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/project/_chatbot-advertising/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/project/_chatbot-advertising/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Powered by artificial intelligence (AI), chatbots are increasingly capable of simulating human-like conversations to enable users to interact with digital devices effectively. But, is this desirable for strategic communications? Will chatbots be more persuasive if they are more human-like, not only in their appearance but also in their interaction and delivery of advertising content? Or will they raise unrealistic user expectations? We explored these questions with a 2 (chatbot profile: human-like vs. machine-like) x 2 (message interactivity: high vs. low) x 2 (ad type: narrative vs. factual) experiment (N = 414). Data reveal that high message interactivity fosters positive attitudes toward the chatbot and the ad by increasing perceptions of social presence, as well as by mitigating violated expectancy. When a chatbot is machine-like in appearance, higher interactivity and adoption of a narrative style of delivery serve to increase ad persuasiveness by heightening social presence. Theoretical as well as practical implications for chatbot advertising are discussed.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/contact/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/contact/contact/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Schadenfreude after watching the news: How audiences respond to media coverage of partisans disclosing illnesses</title>
      <link>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/publication/myrickchen-2022/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/publication/myrickchen-2022/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome to my website</title>
      <link>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/post/2021-12-07/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Dec 2021 14:00:31 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/post/2021-12-07/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Privacy Policy</title>
      <link>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/privacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/privacy/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terms</title>
      <link>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/terms/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Dec 2021 00:00:00 +0100</pubDate>
      <guid>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/terms/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Do You Feel Special When an AI Doctor Remembers You? Individuation Effects of AI vs. Human Doctors on User Experience</title>
      <link>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/publication/chen-et-al-2021/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 May 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://academic-demo.netlify.app/publication/chen-et-al-2021/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
